maximilian klein objective publications

max@notconfusing.com

+17074787023 notconfusing.com

Information Management and Systems PhD

School of Information UC Berkeley

The Virtuous Circle of Wikipedia

03 / 2014

CSCW 2015 · Authors: Maximilian Klein, Thomas Maillart, John Chuang https://github.com/notconfusing/wiki_econ_capability/blob/master/paper/cscw/cscw2015.pdf

Accepted as a paper at CSCW '15, and a poster at NetSci '14, we propose a measure of the "collaborativeness" of a group of socio-technical participants by calibrating correlations between rankings given by an extension of the Google PageRank algorithm and exogenous metrics. Results on the English Wikipedia categories are presented, accurately predicting edit wars and structured organization.

WIGI: Wikipedia Gender Inequality Index

11/2014

In Submission · Authors: Maximilian Klein, Piotr Konieczny

https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Research:Wikipedia Gender Inequality Index

WIGI is an inequality index allowing comparative study of gender inequality through time, space, culture, and language editions. Based on the Wikidata.org dataset, we create a monthly-updated freely licensed dataset for use in academia, as well as historical and sociological observational analysis on the rise of world cultures.

VIAFbot and the Integration of Library Data on Wikipedia

Code4Lib Journal · Authors: Maximilian Klein, Alex Kyrios http://journal.code4lib.org/articles/8964 10/2013

A case study of a project that successfully added authority data to hundreds of thousands of articles on the English Wikipedia, and paved the way for doing so in all other Wikipedias.

experience

Wikiproject Open Access

02 / 2014 - Present

Developer and Researcher

https://github.com/wpoa

Funded by the Open Society Foundations, developed applications watching citations on Wikipedia and uploading the Open Access papers to Wikisource for deeplinking and usage tracking. Meanwhile, the program *recitationBot* outputs *altmetrics* of the number of pageviews a citation is receiving back to academic community.

OCLC Research

05 / 2012 - 03 / 2014

Research Assistant, Wikipedian in Residence

http://hangingtogether.org/?cat=51

Bridging the gap between library data and Wikipedia. Racked up over 2 million Wikipedia edits with custom-written bot to augment article metadata using Library data.

Untrikiwiki

05 / 2012 - Present

Principal

http://untrikiwiki.com/

Founder of Wiki tech company. Notably, as a grantee of Creative Commons extended MediaWiki to support the LRMI educational metadata standard.

education

University of California, Berkeley

2007 - 2011

A.B. , Pure Mathematics

Emphasis in Logic and Abstract Algebra.

Programming Language Proficiencies: Python, Scheme, R, Java.

Sudo Room Hackerspace

2011 - Present

Founding Member and Treasurer

Leader and participant of community education in formal Logic and 3D printing.